Guide to the Veranus A. Moore Papers, 1836-1958
Moore, Veranus A. papers, 1836-1958
- Series VII. Family Papers
  - Alva Moore
    - Diary, 1867 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Antoinette Moore, 1890-1896 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Antoinette Moore's scrapbook, ca. 1880 (Box 35)
  - Edwin Moore, 1909-1912 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Erwin V. Moore
    - Correspondence, 1907, 1917-1926, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Postcards from V.A.M., 1909-1914, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Postcards from others, 1910-1915 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Class Notes - Bacteriology, 1916 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Class Notes - Civics, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Fred F. Moore, 1885-1927 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Mary E. Moore Shackleton
    - Correspondence, 1913-1928, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Ephemera, 1907, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Postcards from V.A.M., 1909-1917 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Postcards from Norman Moore and Mary S. Moore, 1913, 1918, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Postcards from Helena Haight, 1911-1917, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Postcards from others, 1903-1917, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Mary Slawson Moore
    - Correspondence, 1887-1929, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Postcards from V.A.M., 1908-1924 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Postcards from "Winnifred", 1909-1915, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Postcards from Helena Haight, 1911, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Postcards from others, 1908-1919, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Obituaries, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Norman Moore, 1910-1929, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Norman Moore - Postcards from V.A.M., 1903-1917, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Walter J. Moore, 1890-1930 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - W.C. Moore, 1891-1926 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Lulu Moore Manny, 1891-1928, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Lillie Plank, 1889-1898 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Horace Shackleton, 1922-1930, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Unidentified Class Notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1855-1858 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1859-1861 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1862-1867 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1869-1873 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, ca. 1855-1875 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1899-1928, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Schools, 1915-1922 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Ithaca Public Schools, 1912-1921 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Rotary Club, 1919-1942 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - [Ithaca] Chamber of Commerce, 1917-1928 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Hospital, 1920-1930 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Businessmen's Association, 1902-1912 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Savings & Loan, 1915-1929 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Ithaca miscellany, 1898-1929 (Box 44, Folder 8)
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Formal Portraits of Veranus Moore (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Informal Images of Veranus Moore (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Veranus Moore at Work (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Veranus Moore, Mary Moore, and children (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Moore Children - Group Shots (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Moore Children - Erwin V. Moore (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Moore Children - Mary E. Moore (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Moore Children - Norman Moore (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Family Photos (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Veranus Moore and His Brothers (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Other Family Photos (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Cornell and Other Buildings (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Classmates (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - New York State College of Veterinary Medicine (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Cornell People and Miscellaneous Veterinarians (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Identified People (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Partially Identified Adults (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Portraits from Mexico, NY, and Oswego/Syracuse Area (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Columbian University Classmates and Friends (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Veterinary Medicine Subject Photos (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Foot and Mouth Disease (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Moore Children, 1901-1902 - Glass Plate Negatives (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Identified Children (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Men (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified Women (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified Children (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Family and Friends - Negatives (Box 43, Folder 5)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
A small collection of James Law correspondence has been removed and rehoused as its own collection.
Approximately 1 linear foot of material created by Norman Moore has been removed and rehoused with the Norman Moore Papers (RMC # 51-01-1368).
Approximately 1 linear foot of material created by Mary Moore Shackleton has been removed and rehoused with the Shackleton Family collection (RMC # 37-05-3133).
A collection of reprints authored by Veranus Moore has been separated and housed in the Historical Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet collection.
A collection of reprints and pamphlets by other authors has also been removed. Most have been rehoused in the Historical Veterinary Reprint and Pamphlet collection. Some have been discarded. A full list of what has been removed is available below.[ Some of the material in this list is obviously from Norman Moore's work. These items are included in the list but may not be available in the reprint collection.]
No Author
"Koch's tuberculosis conclusions." American Veterinary Review, September 1901.
A
Abel, John. "Chemistry in relation to biology and medicine with especial reference to insulin and other hormones." Reprinted from Science, October 1927.
Abel, Mary Hinman. "Sugar as Food." U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmer's Bulletin No. 93, 1899.
Ackerman, E. B. "Administrative Control of Glanders." Department of Health of the City of New York, Reprint No. 16, April 1914.
Alvord, Henry E. "Statistics of the dairy: Compiled from the United States census for 1890, and from other reliable sources with explanatory notes." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 11, 1896.
Alvord, Henry E. and R. A. Pearson. "The Milk Supply of Two Hundred Cities and Towns." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 46, 1903.
Armsby, Henry Prentiss and J. August Fries. "Energy values of red clover hay and Maize Meal: investigations with the respiration calorimeter, in cooperation with the Pennsylvania State College agricultural experiment station." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 74, 1905.
________ and J. August Fries. "The Available Energy of Red Clover Hay." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 101, 8 January 1908
Arup, Johannes. "Viehversicherungen in Danemark." VIII. Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Atwater, W.O. and Chas D. Woods. "The Chemical Composition of American Food Materials." U.S. Department of Agriculture Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin, No. 28, 1896.
________. "Foods: Nutritive Value and Cost." U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin, No. 23, 1894.
Atwood, George E. and George Hassletine. "Undulant Fever in Ware County, GA." Reprinted from Public Health Reports, 13 June 1930.
Aujeszky, Aladar. "Die Bedeutung der saurefesten, tuberelbacillenahnlichen stabchen bei der beurteilung der untersuchunern auf tuberkulose." VIII Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Ayers, Henry S. "The present status of the pasteurization of milk." U. S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 342, 8 January 1916.
B
Babes, V. "Rapport sur les recherches plus recentes concernant la transmission des maladies des animaux domestiques chez l'homme." VIII. Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
Bailey, L.H. "Dr. L.H. Bailey on the Farm-Bureau Movement." An address by the former director of the New York State College of Agriculture before the Erie County Farm Bureau Association of Buffalo, NY, 17 March 1914.
Baker, J.C. and L.L. Van Slyke. "The Determination of the Keeping Quality of Milk." From Technical Bulletin, No. 72, June 1919.
________. and L.L. Van Slyke. "A Method for the preliminary detection of abnormal milks, No. 71, June 1919.
________. and L.L. Van Slyke. "The reaction of milk in relation to the presence of blood cells and of specific bacterial infections of the udder." Technical Bulletin, No. 80, July 1920.
Baldwin, Edward, R. "The Ophthalmo-Tuberculin diagnotic test." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 14 December 1907.
________ and P.A. Levene. "The action of proteolytic enzymes on bacterial toxins." Reprinted from Journal of Medical Research, Vol. VI, July 1901.
_________. "The problem of immunity in tuberculosis." Reprinted from Transactions of the Sixth International Congress on Tuberculosis, 28 September and 5 October 1908.
Bancroft, Wilder D. and J.E. Rutzler. "Reversible coagulation in living tissue." Reprinted from the proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Vol. 17, April 1931.
Barach, Alvan, L. "The therapeutic use of oxygen in heart disease." Reprinted from Annals of Internal Medicine, Vol. 5, October 1931.
Barker, Lewellys, F. "On the study of anatomy." Reprinted from The Johns Hopkins Hospital Bulletin, Vol. XII, April-June 1901.
________. "The unveiling of the cell." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 1 March 1902.
________. "Progress of Neurology." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 1899.
Barnes, Arlie R. and Merritt B. Whitten. "Study of the R-T interval in myocardial infarction." Reprinted from The American Heart Journal, December 1929.
Bassett, S.H., Evelyn Holt and F.O. Santos. "The Influence of meat upon physical efficiency." Reprinted from The American Journal of Physiology, May 1922.
Beach, J.R. "The effect of feeding bacillus acidophilus, lactose, dry skim milk, or whole milk on the hydrogen ion concentration of the contents of the ceca of chickens." Hilgardia: A Journal of Agricultural Science published by the California agricultural experiment station, October 1925.
________. "Infectious bronchitis of fowls." Reprinted from Journal of American Veterinary Medical Association, February 1926.
________. "Observations on the occurrence of fowl cholera in California." Reprinted from Poultry Science, August - September 1922.
_______. "Suggestions to poultrymen concerning chicken-pox." University of California College of Agriculture Berkeley Circular No. 145, December 1915.
_______ and J.C. Corl. "Studies in the control of avian coccidiosis." Reprinted from Poultry Science, Vol. 4, February-March, 1925.
_______. and D.E. Davis. "Coccidiosis of chickens." University of California College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Circular 300, October 1926.
_______. and D.E. Davis. "The influence of feeding lactose or dry skim milk on artificial infection of chicks with eimeria avium." Hilgardia: a journal of agricultural science published by the California agricultural experiment station, October 1925.
Beal, F.E.L. "Some common birds: in their relation to agriculture." From the U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin, No. 54, 1897.
Bela, Kovacsy. "Az istalloza es legeltetes elettni es allattenyesztesi szempontbol." From VIII. Nemzetkozi Allatorvosi Kongresszus Budapesten, 1905.
Berry, John M. "A Comparison of the phagocytic action of leukocytes in amphibia and mammalia." Reprinted from the Transactions of the Twentieth Annual Meetings of the American Microscopical Society held at Toledo, Ohio, 5-7 August 1897.
Biggs, Hermann M. "Milk-Borne Septic Sore Throat: A New Health Problem." New York State Department of Health, 1915.
________. "Preventive Medicine in the City of New York." The address in public medicine delivered at the 65th annual meeting of the British medical association, in Montreal, Canada, September 1897.
Birch, R.R. "Hog cholera." Cornell Reading Course for the Farm: Livestock Series, Lesson 150, October 1919.
________. "Garbage feeding, and the care of garbage fed swine." Reprinted from the 1918 Report of the New York State Veterinary College.
________. and H.L. Gilman. "Handling Bang Abortion Diseases; a program for the veterinary practitioner." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the New York State Veterinary College at Cornell University, 1927-1928.
________. and H.L. Gilman. "The agglutination test as an aid in handling bang abortion disease." Reprinted from the 1929 Annual report of the state veterinary college.
________. and H.L. Gilman. "Bang abortion disease in cattle." Cornell extension bulletin published by the New York State college of agriculture at Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, Bulletin 137, April 1926.
Bissell, William G. "Municipal water-supplies and their examination." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 30 August 1902.
Bitting, A.W. "Bovine tuberculosis in Indiana." Purdue University Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin, No. 63, December 1896.
Bolton, B.M. "The bacteriolytic power of the blood serum of hogs." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 95, 12 March 1907.
Bongert, J. "Uber die art der infection bei der tuberkulose der haustiere." VIII. Internationaler Tieraztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Bourne, Wesley. "What constitutes an efficient anesthesia service for hospitals." Reprinted from American College of Surgeons, March 1930.
Bowen, John T. "The cost of pasteurizing milk and cream." Bulletin of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, No. 85, 27 April 1914.
Blanchard R. "Substances toxiques produites par les parasites animaux." VIII. Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
Breed, Robert S. and James D. Brew. "The control of bacteria in market milk by direct microscopic examination." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 443, December, 1917.
Brewer, F.W. "Tuberculosis." Agricultural College of Utah Experiment Station, No. 41, 31 December 1895.
Brooks, Paul B. "Two Milk-borne septic sore throat epidemics." Reprinted from American Journal of Public Health, September 1929.
Brower, A. Blaine and Walter M. Simpson. "Antianemic influence of desiccated whole hog stomach." Reprinted from The American Journal of the Medical Sciences, September 1931.
Brown, Charles W. and Kurt Peiser. "Keeping qualities of butter v. pasteurization and its influence, (contribution) a study of the factors which influence the resistance of lactic acid bacteria to heat." Michigan agricultural college experiment station division of bacteriology, Technical Bulletin, No. 30, October 1916.
Bugbee, Henry G. "Diverticulum of the ureter: a report of three cases." Reprinted from The Journal of Urology, August 1931.
________. "Multiple fractures of the pelvis with rupture of he bladder." Reprinted from Transactions of the American Association of Genito-Urinary Surgeons, 1927.
________. "Postoperative care of urological cases." Reprinted from The American journal of surgery, July 1931.
________. and Arthur J. Murphy. "The value and limitations of uroselectan as an aid in urological diagnosis." Reprinted from The Journal of Urology, March 1931.
________. "Silent ureteral calculi." Reprinted from the Transactions of the American Association of Genito-Urinary Surgeons for 1930.
________. "Cases of unsuspected carcinom of the prostate discovered on microscopic section." Reprinted from The Journal of urology, October 1929.
Bullard, Margerite J. "Study of the Bacterial Flora of the Intestinal Mucusa of the Normal Rabbit." American Medicine, 4 October 1902.
Burnett, Samuel H. "The control of an outbreak of anthrax." Reprinted from American Veterinary Review, May 1908.
_______. "Noted on the clinical examination of the blood of the domesticated animals." American Veterinary Review, December 1903.
Busey, Samuel C. "The duties of physicians to the profession and their relation to the medical charities of the district of Columbia." Reprinted from Transactions of the medical society of the District of Columbia, 15 December 1897.
_______. "Compulsory Reports of Zygotic Diseases; Milk Legislation; Medical Practice Law; And Society Publication of its Transactions." Annual Address of the President of the Medical Society of the District of Columbia, 18 December 1895.
Buxton, R.H. "Bacterial Purification of Sewage." Reprinted from The Philadelphia Medical Journal, 5 April 1902.
C
Calvin, Joseph K. and A.H. Goldberg. "Plasma Proteins and Edema: Their relationship in a group of children presenting the nephritic syndrome" Reprinted from the American Journal of Diseases of Children, August 1931.
Campbell, H.C. "Leucocytes in Milk: Methods of Determination and the effect of heat upon their number." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin 117, 1909.
Campell, S.B. Boyd and S.I. Turkington. "Right bundle-branch blook. An analysis of the clinical records of fifty-six cases with typical electrocardiograms" Reprinted from Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931.
Cannon, Walter B. "The dog's gift to the relief of human suffering." Reprinted from Hygenia, January 1926.
Carpenter, Charles M. "Brucella abortus in udders of vaccinated and naturally infected cattle." Cornell Veterinarian, April 1926.
Carter, Edward P. and Benjamin Baker Jr. "Certain aspects of syphilitic cardiac disease." Reprinted from Bulletin of John Hopkins Hospital, May 1931.
Carter, H. R. "Methods of the conveyance of yellow fever infection." United States Treasury Department, Bureau of Public Health and Marine-Hospital Service, Yellow Fever Institute Bulletin No. 10, 1902.
_______. "Shipment of merchandise from a town infected with yellow fever." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, 1899
_______. "Train inspection in yellow fever epidemics." Reprinted from Annual Report Marine-Hospital Service, United States Treasury Department, 1899.
Carter, William Wesley. "The importance of nasal plastic surgery." Reprinted from The Larynogoscope, July 1930.
_______. "Transposition of Section from the Auricle for the Correction of a Nasal Defect." Reprinted from the Archives of Otolaryngology, August 1930.
Cary. C.A. "Bovine tuberculosis." Alabama Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 67, November 1895.
Cattell, J. McKeen. "Some psychological experiments." Reprinted from Science, 1 January and 8 January 1926.
Celi. A and R. Fiocca. "Beitrage zur Amobenforshung. Zweite vorlaufige Mitteilung. Ueber die Klassifikation der Amoben und einige gezuchtete Species." Pasoerorean, May 1894.
Chapin, Charles V. "Some Sanitary Problems." The annual address before the Rhode Island Medical Society, 26 May 1908.
Chester, F.D. "Protective inoculation against anthrax." The Proceedings of the Seventeenth meeting of the Society for the Promotion of Agriculutural Sciences, August 1896.
Church, H.R., M.F. Barnes, W.H. Ridge and F.A. Marshall. "Infectious abortion and sterility" Bulletin of the Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture, December 1921.
Claypole, Agnes Mary. "The enterion of the Cayuga Lake lamprey." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, 1894.
________. "New method for securing paraffin sections to the slide or cover-glass." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, n.d.
Claypole, Edith J. "An Investigation of the blood of necturus and cryptobranchus." Extract from Proceedings, 1893.
Coit, Henry L. "The work of medical milk commissions in the campaign for the betterment of milk production and distribution." Reprinted from Transactions of the Fifteenth International Congress on Hygiene and Demography, 23-28 September 1912.
Connaway, J.W. "Hog Cholder and immature corn." University of Missouri College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 174, September 1920.
Cope, E.D. "On the characters of some Paleozoic fishes." Proceedings of the United States National Museum, 1891.
Cope, C.L. "the excretion of creatinine by the human kidney in health and in nephritis." Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931.
Councilman, W.T., F.B. Mallory and R.M. Pearce. "Diphtheria: a study of the bacteriology and pathology of two hundred and twenty fatal cases." 1901.
Crawley, Howard. "Studies on blood and blood parasites." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 119, 1909.
Curtice, Cooper. "The cattle tick." Reprinted form the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, July 1891.
________. "The oxwarble of the United States." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, June 1891.
_______. "Fowl typhoid." Rholed Island College of Agriculture and Mechaic Arts, Bulletin No. 87 September1902.
D
Davies, Daniel T. "Studies on achlorhydria and anaemia." Reprinted from the Quarterly Journal of Medicine, July 1931.
Dawson Charles F. "Epithelioma contagiosum." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 1 October 1902.
________. "Hog cholera and swine plague." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 15 March 1902.
_______. "Lumpy Jaw." Florida Agricultural experiment station department of veterinary science, 15 June 1902.
_______. "Moon Blindness." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, Bulletin No. 28, 15 July 1902.
_______. "Parturient paralysis." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, 15 April 1902.
_______. "Roup." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science, 1 June 1902.
________. "Some Poultry Pests." Florida Agricultural Experiment Station, Department of Veterinary Science,, 1 January and 15 January 1902.
Day, L. Enos. "Embryonal adenosacromoa of the kidney in swine." Reprinted from the Twenty-Fourth Annual Report of the Bureau of Animal Industry, 1907.
Dearborn, Ned. "Rabbit Growing to Supplement the Meat Supply." Separate from Yearbook of the Department of Agriculture, 1918, No. 784.
De Forest, Henry P. "Blindess of the newborn." Reprinted from the New York Medical Journal, 29 May and 5 June 1915.
_________. "Prostitution personal observations of police methods of dealing with prostituion in Germany." Reprinted form the New York State Journal of Medicine, October 1908.
De Jesus, Zacarias. "The Germicidal Properties of the Mixture of Kerosene and Coconut Oil." Philippine Agriculturist, February 1928.
De Schweinitz, E. A. "The War with the Microbes." Reprinted from Science, 9 April 1897.
_________, Marion Dorset and E.C. Schroeder. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin, No. 52 pt. 2, 1905.
D'Herelle, F. "Annual Graduate Fortnight: bacteriohage as a treatment in acute medical and surgical infections." Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, May 1931.
Dikmans, G. "Two new lungworms form North America ruminants and a note on the lungworms of sheep in the United States." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1931.
Dixon, Samuel G. "Koch's method of treating tuberculosis." Medical News, 17 January 1891.
_________. "Law, Foundatoin of state medicine." Reprinted from the Journal of American Medical Associations, 8 June 1907.
Doan, Charles A. "The clinical implications of experimental hematology." Reprinted from Medicine, September 1931.
Dorset, Marion. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 52 pt.1, 1904.
_________, C.N. McBryde and W. B. Niles." Further experiment concerning the production of immunity from hog cholera." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 102, 1908.
Douglass, Stephan A. and William C. Jensen. "Experience in finding tuberculosis cases in Cattaraugus county." Cattaraugus County Health Demonstration, 1 September 1926.
________. "Sanatorium-home treatment aids tuberculosis fight." Reprinted from The Nation's Health, March 1962.